In this tutorial, we will learn how to make the head of the dragon.
Before starting the modeling in Marvelous Designer, I drew the front and side pictures of the dragon's head,
to make it easier to create the shape of the dragon's head version more accurately.
Then import this picture as a background picture into the 2D window.
First, let's draw the mouth version.
Use a multidirectional tool to draw the mouth version along the side picture.
The concept picture I drew is a draft, and I want to make the width of the lip version more even.
So I need to use the edit curve tool to slightly adjust these curve points.
Use the edit curve tool to adjust the curve points,
press the bottom button to keep the curve points on both sides not affected.
When drawing the lower lip version, we only draw half of the lip version.
Use the edit curve tool to enter the center line on the right-click, select the symmetry to open the edit line.
Then use the adjust curve tool to adjust the size of the lip version.
Then copy and paste a lip version as the upper lip.
Arrange the lip version in the 3D window, pay attention to maintain the connection face direction.
I want to make the back of the upper lip version wider, but the front does not need to be modified too much.
Use the add point line tool to add a cut point to the side version to divide the upper and lower lip.
Then use the free-format tool to merge the pieces together.
The lip version is shorter than the side of the upper lip version.
We need to calculate the length of the missing piece, and lengthen the piece.
Select the side of the lip version.
On the side of the lip version, press and hold the button to expand the lip version.
Enter the difference.
Then slightly adjust the extended part.
Then use the edit curve tool to adjust the curve.
Do the same for the lower lip part.
Copy and paste the upper and lower lip version.
Arrange them in the right position and turn the surface of the lip version.
Let the lip version face out.
Then also merge the side of the newly created lip version on the lip version.
Use the free-format tool to merge them to the equal position.
Harden all the lip versions to make them look harder.
Open the model attribute.
Close the ground conflict in the attribute editor.
Return the gravity to 0.
Open the model.
Once the model is stable, turn off the hardening.
I'm going to use the Fusible Rigid fabric for the upper and lower lip versions.
This fabric is very hard and not easy to deform.
Then apply the Fulgrain Leather fabric to the side lip version.
It is not easy to bend and not easy to fold.
Use the sticky layer for the lip version.
In the preset attribute below, select Reinforcement Pocket Bone.
This is a very hard fabric.
As a sticky layer, tapping on the original fabric will increase the hardness.
Open the model.
You can see that the side version becomes closer to the original shape in the 2D window.
Then insert the forehead file carved in ZBrush.
If you have searched for the production method of the Chinese five dragon,
you will find that the internal structure of the dragon head is actually completed by the frame and paper or cloth.
We can imitate this structure.
Now put your mouth under your forehead.
Switch to the top view.
Adjust the top two versions.
Make them close to the shape of the forehead.
After modifying the top and back versions, adjust the side versions to simulate.
In order to prevent the position of the version from moving, you can temporarily freeze the top version.
In the 3D window, move all the box versions upwards.
Freeze other versions.
Separately simulate the top version.
Then use the linear virtual model tool to draw the area along the forehead model.
Start drawing from the front of the nose here.
Click to create a straight line point.
Press Ctrl and click to draw a straight line point.
You can freely draw these lines on the model.
These lines will become the contact points between the line and the line.
This step is a bit like a retouch.
Draw a large division, and then draw these versions according to the need.
When drawing to extract the area, be careful to avoid the position near the eyeball.
And ensure that the shape is closed.
If you want to adjust these points, you can use the linear virtual model tool to drag them.
When the structure is completed, we will extract the version from the model.
Use the flat flat version tool to select all areas to extract the version.
Then press the Enter key to extract the version.
Place the extracted version in the 2D window.
Select the version on this side.
Press Ctrl to align the version.
Then sew the balance line in the middle.
Then apply the full grain leather fabric to these versions.
Open the simulation.
You will see that the entire head version has no wrinkles.
The seam allowance is also relatively smooth.
Then adjust the section of the version.
Try to keep the corner of the bottom of the front as straight as possible.
This way, the left and right sides are balanced together, which is a flat corner.
The transition will be smooth.
For other positions, you can refer to the effect in the 3D window.
For example, if the side is short, select the related points.
Drag out the missing part.
Or adjust the curve by clicking the edit curve tool.
Then sew the forehead version and the lower jaw part together.
Use the n-to-n sewing tool to sew the two side versions together.
For the front nose version, I want to keep the shape of the nose.
So I need to fill in the parts that are out of the middle.
Select the front, middle and bottom lines.
Expand the outline of the line.
Change the side angle to Extend.
And select the inner line.
Select the inner line.
Then cut and sew the extra part.
Then adjust the length of this version.
And sew it together with the lips version.
Then draw a triangle version to fill in the gap.
Sew the upper and lower versions together and simulate.
After simulation, modify the version.
Fill in the rest of the area.
After modification, remember to apply the material FULL GRAND LEVEL.
Select the eye structure.
In the right-click menu, select Reactive Virtual Model.
Then select these lines that form the eye frame.
At the bottom of the 2D line length of the attribute editor,
you can find the total length of these lines.
Use the round tool to click the 2D window to measure the total length.
As a circle, create a circle.
Rotate the circle to match any of its straight lines with the straight lines of other versions.
Freeze all other versions and activate the round version.
Use the 3D arrangement tool.
After doing this, the round version will be in the same position as the 2D window.
The straight lines will match.
Convenient for subsequent sewing.
Then activate the 3D version.
Then activate all versions to simulate and print the ball shape versions.
Then use the 3D version tool for the line segment to model the lines based on the ball shape model.
Use the 3D version tool for the edit point line to select.
Transform the 3D section into the inner shape.
To eliminate unnecessary dots,
we use the optimization curve dot function.
After optimization is complete, manually delete the excess curve points or manually adjust the curve points.
Select the inner line, then select the section.
Delete the excess part.
Then activate the eyeball model.
Finally, use the Stabilizer to increase the Stabilizer for the grid points around the eyes, and then fix the Stabilizer to the virtual model.
Open the simulation.
Next, let's complete the back of the head.
Use the Stabilizer to draw a shape in the 3D window again.
Take these shapes out of the Stabilizer.
Mix the panels together.
Stretch the panels.
In the 3D window, use the 3D panel tool to draw a cut line.
Use the 3D panel tool to draw a cut line along the cut panel.
Use the Stabilizer tool to select the panel in front of this panel and the Stabilizer in front of this panel.
Right-click on the start point of the Stabilizer to add a point.
Now we can easily see the starting point of the Stabilizer and then create the Stabilizer.
Then, based on the connection points of the lower panel, draw a small panel.
After mixing, continue to modify the shape.
Now, create a circle.
Change to the second channel one.
Use the 3D panel tool to create a circle.
Use the Stabilizer tool to create a circle.
Now, I will use the 3D panel tool to create a circle.
Switch to the back view, and calculate the total length of the panel in the back of this circle, and then create a round panel.
Refer to the 3D window effect to flatten the top of the panel.
Using the n-to-n
tool, combine the new panel with this circle.
Use the 3D panel tool to draw the reference position of the dragon's feet.
Then adjust the curve according to the test picture of the head.
Create a symmetrical panel according to the need to adjust the curve.
Since the line of the symmetrical panel will be created in a symmetrical way,
we need to remove the joint first, then create a line of lines,
and then increase the pressure of the panel to create the filling effect of the feet.
Hardening the panel makes it difficult for the panel to bend,
and the position of the panel seam will be smoother.
Now the basic panel of our head
is finished.
Next, we will add some details to the dragon's head.
First, we will make the dragon's tongue.
Use the chin panel to draw the tongue panel.
All you need to do is draw half of the panel,
then align it to open the editor.
Use the test picture to draw the side of the tongue.
If the center of the tongue is not connected,
you can now draw the original portion.
Use the Але opened image to create the team of lines.
We can again use the pinch function to maintain the shape of the side panel, and thus complete the effect of curving the tongue.
Using the width and height of the tongue, add a line function to the internal line border to create an internal rectangle, and then merge the tongue into the internal rectangle.
Next, use the same method to create the side hair.
Adjust the side hair to the lip side, and then cut off the excess part according to the outline and merge the internal line.
Repeat the steps to complete the rest of the side hair.
personas
Due to the thickness of the character of each panel, if it is weave over too many layers on the same side, it may be unbalanced or unstable.
multiple layers
In order to make these panels more stable and flat, we need to create a panel that is specifically used for the panel.
Draw a rectangular panel according to the length of the lip panel.
Select the top and bottom two edges, and draw two inner lines according to the depth of the curve line.
Combine this little strip to the side of the lip panel.
In the 3D window, select this panel, and then select to add it to the outside, so that you can quickly arrange the panel.
Repeat this step to make another panel inside the lip.
Then copy the lip panel and arrange it to the outside of the original lip.
Use the panel outline to expand the outer layer of the lip panel, and the expanded part will cover the seam.
Then expand the panel outline to automatically generate the inner line,
and merge it with the other side of the middle strip.
Print the panel to quickly complete the structure.
Now we can merge the panel to the middle strip.
Then you can continue to add the panel on the side.
You can refer to the 3D window and the 2D window for the effect at any time.
To modify the panel,
For the dragon's feet version, I want to make some silk pleats to wrap the effect.
Select the dragon's feet version, then select the outer layer of the dragon, and create an outer layer version.
Increase the fineness of the dragon's feet version, and increase the size of the outer layer version.
Add Silk Crepe D-Chain as the material attribute, and apply this attribute to the outer layer version.
The outer layer version has folds due to increased shrinkage, so reduce the shrinkage and remove some folds.
Change the color of the fabric to gold, and change the type to silk.
Next, let's make the eyebrows.
Change the color of the eyebrows to black, and change the type to silk.
After drawing, sew it on the eye.
Next, let's make the eyes.
Use the 3D panel function to draw the nose part on the panel.
Then convert it to the inner line.
Adjust its shape in the 2D window.
Select the line of the nose panel, and use the outline tool to set this part as a panel.
After dividing the panel, use the add to outer function to arrange the panel.
The ball in the mouth of the dragon's head is the beach volleyball panel used.
The fabric around it is the leather fabric that should not be bent.
Change the type of the fabric to metal.
Use the sewing needle function to fix the ball on the tongue.
We can also use the sewing needle to fix the bottom of the tongue to the jawline.
Next, freeze the other panels.
Use the inner panel of the mouth to make an in-focus effect with a negative pressure.
Finally, let's make the beard.
Repeat these steps to complete the wonken.
To shorten the unit length마a 2.8cm,
adjust the center of gravity to 50 cm,
and make it as deep as possible.
you